Jack Rugile

Front End Web & Game Developer

Email: jack@jackrugile.com Phone: (970) 379-4748 Location: Palm Bay, FL Portfolio: jackrugile.com LinkedIn/GitHub: @jackrugile

I'm a front end web and game developer with 10+ years experience ranging from small creative studios to large corporations. My ambition is to create interactive experiences that bring people joy and solve problems. I take pride in my work and want to leave the web better than I found it. I'm looking to collaborate with a team of innovative professionals who are dedicated to their craft.

Experience

Consume & CreateLead DeveloperDec 2023 - Apr 2024

Senior Developer Aug 2021 - Dec 2023

- » Worked primarily with Vue.js/Nuxt, Sanity, Contentful, Cloudflare, and Netlify to create engaging experiences that clients could control themselves.
- » Developed a web app utilizing the Web Speech API (Speech Recognition) to reduce the use of jargon and unnecessary language in meetings.
- » Used Three.js and device orientation events to create an interactive 360° photo tour of two New Belgium Brewing locations.

The North FaceSenior Interactive Web DeveloperApr 2021 – Jul 2021Interactive Web DeveloperJul 2019 – Apr 2021

- » Successfully launched custom sites and campaigns for product lines such as Futurelight, Vectiv, Black Series, and the Braindead.
- » Built a collection of reusable Vue.js components that could be be flexibly used for multiple campaigns and adhered to brand style guidelines.
- » Guided and mentored two developers on my team to create a productive and communicative department.

Legwork Studio Front End Developer Feb 2017 – May 2019

- » Worked on a variety of projects including campaigns and games for companies like YouTube, Dominos, and Capital One.
- $\ \ \text{``Created a morphing WebGL particle system for a landing hub for OMNIA, a reputable set of international nightclubs.}$
- » Leveraged React, Vue.js, Three.js, Pixi.js, Phaser, and many other tools alongside vanilla JavaScript.

The Firm Graphics Front End Developer Apr 2011 - Feb 2017

- » Focused primarily on music industry sites for clients such as Electric Daisy Carnival, Electric Forest, Michael Franti, and The String Cheese Incident.
- » Created a schedule building app that allowed festival goers to plan and share their experience on social media.
- » Built custom WordPress themes and admin functionality to make the CMS experience as flexible as possible for clients.

Skills

Core	Libraries & Frameworks	Other	Personal
» HTML	» Vue.js/Nuxt	» VS Code	» Husband of lovely wife
» CSS/Sass	» React	» Git (GitHub/Bitbucket)	» Father of two wild boys
» JavaScript	» Three.js	» Build (Vite/Webpack/Parcel/Gulp)	» Music maker
» Accessibility	» GSAP	» Deploy (Netlify/Cloudflare)	» PC gamer
» Performance	» Pixi.js	» CMS (Sanity/Contentful/WordPress)	» Coffee consumer
» SEO	» Phaser	» Design (Adobe CC/Figma)	» Beer imbiber

Education

The Art Institude of Colorado

Associate of Applied Science (AAS)

Web Design and Interactive Media

May 2009 - Mar 2011

» Graduated Summa Cum Laude and received the John Jellico Scholarship.